Finding Aid for the Kichimatsu Taguchi papers, 1909-1935 LSC.2010.32
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kichimatsu Taguchi papers
1909-1935
UCLA Library Special Collections
Taguchi, Kichimatsu
LSC.2010.32
2 oversize_boxes
Kichimatsu Taguchi was born in 1881 in Yamaguchi Prefecture, Japan. He arrived in Hawaii in 1900; settled in Colorado ca. 1908. He was the owner of the Taguchi Company and joint owner of Manzanola Farming Company, both in Rocky Ford, Colorado. This collection consists of business records related to the shipment of cantaloupes harvested in Rocky Ford, Colorado, in association with George N. Dobashi, and personal correspondence. The collection also contains account books related to the Taguchi Company and Manzanola Farming Company. Some of the collection is in Japanese.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942338503606533
Biography
Kichimatsu Taguchi was born 1881; a native of Yamaguchi Prefecture, he arrived in Hawaii in 1900; settled in Colorado ca. 1908; owner of the Taguchi Company and joint owner of Manzanola Farming Company, both in Rocky Ford, Colorado.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of business records and personal correspondence related to businessman Kichimatsu Taguchi. The collection contains business records related to the shipment of cantaloupes harvested in Rocky Ford, Colorado, in association with George N. Dobashi, and includes correspondence, telegrams, bills, and receipts (1914-29). The collection also contains account books related to the Taguchi Company and Manzanola Farming Company (1909-35).
Materials in this collection are in English and Japanese.
Additional Physical Form Available
A copy of the original version of this online finding aid is available at the UCLA Department of Special Collections for in-house consultation and may be obtained for a fee. Please contact:
Public Services Division
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library
Box 951575
Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575
Telephone: 310/825-4988 (10:00 a.m. - 4:45 p.m., Pacific Time)
Email: spec-coll@library.ucla.edu
Related Material
Japanese American Research Project Collection of Material about Japanese in the United States (Collection 2010). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Business records.; Ledgers (account books).; Japanese Americans -- Colorado -- Archives.; Businessmen -- Colorado -- Archives.; Japanese American Research Project (University of California, Los Angeles); Taguchi, Kichimatsu--Archives.
- Taguchi Papers, 3 linear ft.
  Scope and Contents note
  Taguchi Kichimatsu [characters] (1881- ). Merchant, Rocky Ford, Colorado. A native of Yamaguchi Prefecture who arrived in Hawaii in 1900 and transmigrated to mainland United States in 1904. Resident of Colorado from about 1908.
  - Miscellaneous Business Records, 1914-1929; 0.5 linear ft.
    Chiefly on the shipment of cantaloupes from Rocky Ford, which Taguchi contracted in partnership with another Japanese, George N. Dobashi. Includes a few personal papers.
    - Personal correspondence of Taguchi., September 1913-February 1915; (11 items) (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - Business correspondence on the shipment of cantaloupes., May 1914-July 1916; (69 items) (Box 143, Folder 2)
    - Telegrams exchanged on the shipment of cantaloupes., August-October 1915; (60 pieces) (Box 143, Folder 3)
    - Shipment records., August-October 1915 & August 1916; (5 items) (Box 143, Folder 4)
    - Reports on marketing information by the Department of Agriculture, Office of Markets and Rural Organization., September 1915; (7 items) (Box 143, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous business records., August-November 1915; (12 pieces) (Box 143, Folder 6)
    - Copy of a lease agreement., July 1916; (1 item) (Box 143, Folder 7)
    - Bills and receipts., December 1910, October 1913, August-October 1915, and August-October 1916.; (107 pieces) (Box 143, Folder 8)
    - Statements on Taguchi's railroad damage claim of 1922., June 10, 1924; (2 pieces) (Box 143, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous business correspondence., March-April 1929; (5 pieces) (Box 143, Folder 10)
  - Account books of the Taguchi Company and the Mansanola Farming Company in Rocky Ford, Colorado, 1909-1935; 2.5 linear ft. (4 account books)
    - An expense account book, covering the period August 1915-May 1924, of the Manzanola Farming Company owned jointly by 4 Japanese including Taguchi in Rocky Ford, Colorado., (1 account book) (Box 144)
    - 3 cash books of the Taguchi Company., April 1909-December 1935; (3 account books) (Box 144)
    - Payment records of Japanese customers, Taguchi Company., ca. 1913-1915; (4 account books) (Box 144)
    - The Taguchi Company's ledgers., April 1909-December 1931; (4 account books) (Box 724)
    - The Taguchi Company's ledger., 1927-1932; (1 account book) (Box 725)